Welcome to Australia!
Australia is a adventure, romance, drama film directed by Baz Luhrmann.
Set in northern Australia before World War II, an English aristocrat who inherits a sprawling ranch
reluctantly pacts with a stock-man in order to protect her new property from a takeover plot.
As the pair drive 2,000 head of cattle over unforgiving landscape, they
experience the bombing of Darwin by Japanese forces firsthand.
Lady Sarah Ashley, played by Nicole Kidman.
The Drover, played by Hugh Jackman.
Katherine, played by Essie Davis.
Neil Fletcher, played by David Wenham.
King Carney, played by Bryan Brown.
King George, played by David Gulpilil.
Australia is a 2008 epic adventure drama film directed by Baz
Luhrmann and starring Nicole Kidman and Hugh Jackman.
The screenplay was written by Luhrmann and screenwriter Stuart
Beattie, with Ronald Harwood and Richard Flanagan.
The film is a character story, set between 1939 and 1942 against a dramatised backdrop of events across northern Australia at the time, such as
the bombing of Darwin during World War II, and government policies of seizing half-caste Aboriginal children then in effect.
Production took place in Sydney, Darwin, Kununurra and Bowen.
The film was released in cinemas on 26 November 2008 in Australia and the United States and on 26 December 2008 in the United Kingdom,
with subsequent worldwide release dates throughout late December 2008, and January and February 2009, by 20th Century Fox.
Australia received mixed reviews from critics and
grossed $211 million worldwide.
On 26 November 2023, Faraway Downs, an extended version of the film presented in the form of a six-episode
mini-series, debuted on Disney+ in Australia, Disney+ Hotstar in India and Hulu in the US.
The film explores themes of australia, missionary,
world war ii, ranch, cattle drive.
The tone is emotional.